Inventory of the United States Office of War Information miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
United States Office of War Information miscellaneous records
1941-1945
XX454
United States. Office of War Information
8 manuscript boxes 2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, press releases, memoranda, clippings, and photographs, relating to regulation of the wartime economy in the United States, and to background information on various countries during World War II and dissemination of American propaganda. Includes a study entitled "Chronology of Adolf Hitler's Life" (1944), prepared as a reference source for the Office of War Information staff.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American governmental agency for dissemination of war information and propaganda during World War II.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, press releases, memoranda, clippings, and photographs, relating to regulation of the wartime economy in the United States, and to background information on various countries during World War II, and to dissemination of American propaganda. Includes a study entitled "Chronology of Adolf Hitler's Life" (1944), prepared as a reference source for the Office of War Information staff.
Related Materials
Records of the Office of War Information [OWI], Record Group 208, National Archives and Records Administration http://www.archives.gov/research/guide-fed-records/groups/208.html
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945.; Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; National socialism.; Propaganda, American.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
Collection Contents
- Country background documents, circa 1941-1945 (Folder 1-2)
  - Albania (Folder 1: 1)
  - Austria (Folder 1: 2)
  - Baltic States (Folder 1: 3)
  - Belgium (Folder 1: 4)
  - Brazil (Folder 1: 5)
  - Bulgaria (Folder 1: 6)
  - Burma (Folder 1: 7)
  - Canada (Folder 1: 8)
  - Chinese Coast, Hainan Coast (Folder 1: 9)
  - Crete (Folder 1: 10)
  - Czechoslovakia (Folder 1: 11)
  - Denmark (Folder 1: 12)
  - Finland (Folder 1: 13)
  - Formosa (Folder 1: 14)
  - France (Folder 1: 15)
  - Germany (Folder 1: 16)
  - Greece (Folder 1: 17)
  - Holland (Folder 1: 18)
  - Hungary (Folder 1: 19)
  - Indo-China (Folder 1: 20)
  - Iran (Folder 1: 21)
  - Istrian Peninsula (Folder 1: 22)
  - Italy (Folder 1: 23)
  - Japan - reference file (Folder 1: 24)
  - Korea (Folder 1: 25)
  - Luxembourg (Folder 1: 26)
  - Malay Peninsula (Folder 1: 27)
  - Manchuria (Folder 1: 28)
  - Maps-Photo (Folder 2: 1)
  - Mexico (Folder 2: 2)
  - Mid-Pacific Islands (Folder 2: 3)
  - Mongolia (Folder 2: 4)
  - Netherlands (Folder 2: 5)
  - Norway (Folder 2: 6)
  - Philippines (Folder 2: 7)
  - Poland (Folder 2: 8)
  - Portugal (Folder 2: 9)
  - Press reference (Folder 2: 10)
  - Production (Folder 2: 11)
  - Relief and Postwar (Folder 2: 12)
  - Rumania (Folder 2: 13)
  - Russia (Folder 2: 14)
  - Sakhalin-Kurile Islands (Russia) (Folder 2: 15)
  - San Marino (Folder 2: 16)
  - Spain (Folder 2: 17)
  - Sweden (Folder 2: 18)
  - Thailand (Folder 2: 19)
  - United Nations (Folder 2: 20)
  - USA background (Folder 2: 21)
  - Yugoslavia (Folder 2: 22)
- Occupied China situation report, 1945 (Folder 3: 1)
- Reports on Japan, 1945 (Folder 3: 2)
- "Chronology of Adolf Hitler's Life", 1944 (Folder 3: 3)
- Japanese Personal Intelligence Volume I, 1945 (Folder 3: 4)
- Japanese Personal Intelligence Collation Volume I, 1945 (Folder 3: 5)
- Japanese Personal Intelligence Volume II, 1945 (Folder 4: 1)
- Japanese Personal Intelligence Volume III, 1945 (Folder 4: 2)
- Operations Intelligence, 1944 (Folder 4: 3-6)
- Operations Intelligence, 1944 (Folder 5: 1-3)
- War Production Board, 1942 (Folder 5: 4-10)
- War Production Board, 1942-1943 (Folder 5: 11)
- War Production Board, 1943 (Folder 5: 12)
- War Production Board, 1943 (Folder 6: 1-6)
- War Production Board, 1944 (Folder 6: 7)
- War Production Board, 1945 (Folder 6: 8-11)
- Washington D.C. press clip sheet, 1943 (Folder 7: 1)
- Defense Transportation, 1942 (Folder 7: 2)
- Office of Defense Transportation, 1942 (Folder 7: 3)
- U.S. Employment Service, 1945 (Folder 7: 4)
- War Manpower Commission, 1942 (Folder 7: 5)
- War Manpower Commission, 1943 (Folder 7: 6-9)
- War Manpower Commission, 1944 (Folder 7: 10-13)
- War Manpower Commission, 1945 (Folder 7: 14)
- War Manpower Commission, 1945 (Folder 8: 1-3)
- Office of Civilian Defense, 1941 (Folder 8: 4)
- National Defense Mediation Board, 1942 (Folder 8: 5)
- U.S. Department of Labor, 1943 (Folder 8: 6)
- National War Labor Board, 1942 (Folder 8: 7)
- Office of Production Management, 1942 (Folder 8: 8)
- Office for Emergency Management, 1942 (Folder 8: 9)
- Office of Price Administration, 1941 (Folder 8: 10)
- Office of Price Administration, 1942 (Folder 8: 11-14)
- Office of Price Administration, 1943 (Folder 8: 15)
- Office of Price Administration, 1944 (Folder 8: 16)
- Office of Price Administration, 1945 (Folder 8: 17)
- Office of War Information, 1943 (Folder 8: 18)
- Office of War Information, 1944 (Folder 8: 19)